{
    "id": "4f10fd3ad5cf40eb92440edfcb138a59",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She ………………………….. to be an architect.",
            "description": "She is a singular subject. Hence we use does here. Note that we write 'does not want', not 'does not wants'.",
            "answers": [
                "does not wants",
                "does not want",
                "do not want"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… forget to lock the door before you leave.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative sentences and in the simple present tense we make questions and negatives with do. ",
            "answers": [
                "Don't",
                "Doesn't",
                "Not"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… not waste any more time.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative sentences.",
            "answers": [
                "Do",
                "Does",
                "Did"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………….with her parents.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "living",
                "live"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was a kind guy who never …………………………… his servants.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "abuses",
                "has abused",
                "abused"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………………… up at 6 am.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "wake",
                "wakes",
                "waking"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………….. him at once.",
            "description": "When we say when something happened, we use the simple past.",
            "answers": [
                "recognizes",
                "recognized",
                "has recognized"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………. a movie yesterday.",
            "description": "We cannot use the present perfect tense with a past time expression. ",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "watch",
                "have watched"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Heavy rains ……………………….. the town yesterday.",
            "description": "When we say when something happened, we use the simple past.",
            "answers": [
                "lashed",
                "lashes",
                "have lashed"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. him twice before he went abroad.",
            "description": "Either simple past or past perfect can be used here. ",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t remember where I ………………………………. my purse.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "have left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………. a snake in the garden.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "see",
                "seen"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}